<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on Moro Bamber</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on Moro Bamber</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! My name is Moro Bamber and I am 24 years old from Toronto, Canada. I am a recent graduate of the University of Alaska Anchorage with a BS in Computer Science. I am interested in many things; including financial markets, computer networks, building software, skiing, climbing, music, and more. Having a background in competitive ski racing has given me key attributes to be succseful in life. I am disciplined, hardworking, and a team player.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello&#34;&gt;Hello!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Moro Bamber and I am 24 years old from Toronto, Canada. I am a recent graduate of the University of Alaska Anchorage with a BS in Computer Science. I am interested in many things; including financial markets, computer networks, building software, skiing, climbing, music, and more. Having a background in competitive ski racing has given me key attributes to be succseful in life. I am disciplined, hardworking, and a team player. In my studies at UAA, I transitioned from pursuing a degree in Mechanical Engineering to Computer Science due to my newfound interest in computer programming. It was something that I thoroughly enjoyed and wanted to do more of. Along the way I have discovered a passion for problem solving through code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last summer, I was fortunate enough to complete a 4 month internship at the Royal Bank of Canada in their Global Markets program.
I sat with the ETF trading desk and worked with them to maintain and develop their backend systems. I have accepted an offer to join RBC Capital Markets full-time in summer 2025 in Toronto as an analyst in their Global Markets division. I am currently a ski racing coach for the Alyeska Ski Club in Girdwood, AK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ME&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/me.jpg&#34;&gt;Me Presenting my Senior Capstone Project on Automobile Crashes in Alaska&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
